Guide to the Rand School of Social Science Records TAM.007
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Course Records, 1917-1955
  - Subseries IIIA: Course Records and Correspondence, 1925-1953
    - "What New Order for Europe?", Course Records and Correspondence, Jul 19, 1941-Oct 1, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      Film R-7124, Reel 43: Frame XIII:C:73
    - Women's Afternoon Classes, Course Announcements and outlines, 1933, 1940, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
      Film R-7124, Reel 43: Frame XIII:C:74
    - Women's Afternoon Classes, Course Outlines and Correspondence, Aug 23, 1941-Jan 25, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      Film R-7124, Reel 43: Frame XIII:C:75
    - Women's Afternoon Forum, Correspondence, Jun 4, 1947-Nov 19, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 43: Frame XIII:C:76
    - Workers' Training Course, Records, 1927-1936 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 43: Frame XIII:C:77
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1930-1931 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 43: Frame XIII:C:78
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1931-1932 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1931-1932 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1932-1933 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1932-1933 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1933-1934 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1933-1934 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1934-1935 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Workers' Training Course, Applications for Scholarships, 1941-1942 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Young People's Socialist League Courses, Jan 9, 1935-Oct 26, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:79
    - Youth Forum, Correspondence, Sep 25, 1945-Apr 1, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:80
    - Youth Leadership, Course Correspondence, Dec 16, 1937, 1938 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:81
    - Youth School, May 24, 1944, Oct 16, 1945, undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:82
  - Subseries IIIB: Miscellaneous Records, 1917-1955
    Miscellaneous Records, consisting of 25 subject files, includes attendance records, biographical information on faculty members and guest lecturers, job applications, registration records, Rand School theatrical group papers, and papers relating to youth affairs. The subject files in this part are arranged in alphabetical order according to the title of the file. Items within each file are arranged in chronological order.
    There are several interesting files in the miscellaneous records. Foremost among these items are the papers pertaining to the Rand School Women's Committee and Women's Auxiliary (XIII:C:99 XIII:C:102). The correspondence and minutes in these particular files relate to the special courses and the 1935 rummage sale which were sponsored by the Women's Committee. Another important segment of this part are the papers of the various Rand School theatrical groups, particularly the Labor Theatre (XIII:C:92), Rand Playhouse (XIII:C:93), and the Workers' Theatre Council (XIII:C:104). Included within these files are plays, routine correspondence, invitations to productions, handbills, and other items. The miscellaneous records also contain some minutes of the International Council for the Study of European Problems (XIII:C:90), records and correspondence for the Trade Union Essay Contest in 1937 (XIII:C:97), records and correspondence for the WEVD Radio Round Table in 1937 (XIII:C:98), and a file on the Young People's Socialist League and the Socialist Party's Committee on Youth Affairs (XIII:C:106).
    - Alumni Committee, Feb 13, 1940, May 14, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:83
    - Class Attendance Records, Fall 1933 -Fall 1937 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:84
    - Class Attendance Records, Winter 1938 -Winter 1939 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Class Attendance Records, Fall 1941 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Class Attendance Records, Fall 1942 -Spring 1943 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Class Attendance Records, Spring 1944-Spring 1946 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Class Attendance Records, Fall 1946 -Winter 1947 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Class Attendance Records, Winter, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Class Attendance Records, undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Joshua Wanhope, Attendance Report on his class entitled, "Introduction to Socialism", Nov 1917-Jan 1918 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:85
    - Attendance at Discussion Groups, 1931 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:86
    - Class Attendance Records, Trade Union Institute Courses, Spring 1944-Spring 1946 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:87
    - Attendance Cards, Re: Meeting with Jan Brommer, Sep 15, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:88
    - Instructor Lists and Biographical Material, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:89
    - Instructor Lists and Biographical Material, undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - International Council for the Study of European Problems, Minutes, Dec 7, 1940-Feb 1, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:90
    - Job Application Materials, Dec 28, 1938-Aug 31, 1940 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:91
    - Job Application Materials, Jan 16, 1941-Sep 17, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Job Application Materials, Sep 23, 1941-Dec 1941 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Job Application Materials, Jan 13, 1942-1943, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Job Application Materials, Jun 5, 1944-Nov 21, 1947, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Labor Theatre, Apr 25, 1953-Jun 1, 1954, undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:92
    - Rand Playhouse, Apr 5, 1931-Oct 5, 1935, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:93
    - Rand School Fellowship, 1926-1936, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 44: Frame XIII:C:94
    - Registration Reports, 1922-1955, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:95
    - Registration Reports, 1922-1955, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Student Course Evaluations, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:96
    - Student Course Evaluations, Feb 5, 1951-Apr 6, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Trade Union Essay Contest, Records and Corres­pondence, Mar 1937-Apr 1937 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:97
    - WEVD Radio Round Table, Records and Correspondence, Jan 21, 1937-May 22, 1937 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:98
    - Women's Committee, Correspondence, Jan 20, 1926-Oct 29, 1947, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:99
    - Women's Committee, Correspondence, Jan 20, 1926-Oct 29, 1947, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Women's Committee: Rummage and Thrift Sale Committee, Correspondence, Oct 25, 1935-Jan 27, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:100
    - Women's Auxiliary, Correspondence, Dec 26, 1950, 1951, undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:101
    - Women's Auxiliary, Minutes, Dec 5, 1950-Mar 21, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:102
    - Workers' Education, Dec 4, 1940-Feb 26, 1944, undated (Box 35, Folder 14)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:103
    - Workers' Theatre Council, 1931-1935, undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:104
    - Workmen's Circle, May 4, 1935-Feb 1, 1951, undated (Box 35, Folder 16)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:105
    - Young People's Socialist League and Socialist Party's Committee on Youth Affairs, Mar 1931-Jan 1936, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:106
    - Young People's Socialist League and Socialist Party's Committee on Youth Affairs, Mar 1931-Jan 1936, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Young People's Socialist League and Socialist Party's Committee on Youth Affairs, Aug 1932-Feb 1933 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Youth Committee, Correspondence and Minutes, Apr 11, 1946-May 1946 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:107
  - Subseries IIIC: Transcripts of Lectures and Debates., 1920-1945
    Transcripts of Lectures and Debates is composed of 36 subject files. These files have been arranged in chronological order, with undated items placed at the end of the section. Among the most interesting items in this part are an address by Bertrand Russell on post World War I Europe (XIII:C:109), a lecture by Stuart Chase on the rationalization of industry (XII:C:111), five lectures by Morris Hillquit on international socialism (XIII:C:112), a debate between Harry Elmer Barnes and Algernon Lee on the question of whether the United States should become involved in an anti fascist war (XIII:C:123), a lecture by Sidney Hook on Marx and Engels (XIII:C:126), and a lecture by Bertram D. Wolfe on Trotsky and Stalin (XIII:C:129). In this part are also transcripts of five "Round Table Discussions" which were sponsored by the Rand school in 1945 (XIII:C:138 XIII:C:142). These discussions, which centered upon a variety of contemporary political topics, featured such prominent figures as Sidney Hook, Bertram D. Wolfe, David J. Dallin, Henry Pratt Fairchild, A. Philip Randolph, and Irving Fisher. A full bibliographical citation for each item in this part can be found in the complete reel list for this collection.
    - "Shall the Policy of the United States Toward Russia Be Changed", a debate between Sen. Joseph I. France of Maryland and Sen. William H. King of Utah, 60pp., ca. Mar 27, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:108
    - "The European Chaos", address by Bertrand Russell, 36pp., Apr 5, 1924 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:109
    - "Mechanism and Life", address by Bertrand Russell, 32 pp., May 3, 1924 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:110
    - "Machinery and Rationalization of Industry", lecture for the course on "American Civilization Today" by Stuart Chase, 29 pp., Oct 20, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:111
    - "Problems of World Socialism", a series of five lectures by Morris Hillquit, 163pp. (The first lecture has two copies)., Nov 12, 1930-Dec 17, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:112
    - "The Business Cycle", lecture by Wesley C. Mitchell, 30 pp., Dec 1, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:113
    - "International Relations", lecture for the course in "American Civilization Today" by Professor James T. Shotwell, 30 pp., Dec 15, 1930 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:114
    - "Changing Concepts of Law", address by Morris R. Cohen, 47 pp., Feb 23, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:115
    - "Industrial Society and the School System", lecture by George S. Counts, 34 pp., Jan 12, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 13)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:116
    - "Industrial Development & Political Philosophy", address by Morris Hillquit, 34 pp., Mar 2, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 14)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:117
    - "The Metropolis in the Machine Age", lecture by Lewis Mumford, 32 pp., Jan 5, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 15)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:118
    - "Social Reality and Imaginative Literature", lecture by Carl Van Doren 48 pp., Jan 19, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 16)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:119
    - "Ethical Ideals in an Industrial Age", lecture by Harry F. Ward, 34 pp., Feb 16, 1931 (Box 36, Folder 17)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:120
    - "The Problem of Experience", the first lecture in a series of three lectures entitled, "Problems of Contemporary Philosophy", by John Dewey, 24 pp., Mar 8, 1933 (Box 36, Folder 18)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:121
    - "Industrial Unionism vs. Craft Unionism", lecture by John P. Frey 48 pp., Apr 24, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 19)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:122
    - "Should the United States Keep Out of Anti-Fascist War?", a debate between Dr. Harry Elmer Barnes and Algernon Lee, 11 pp., Mar 24, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 20)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:123
    - "Should President Roosevelt Seek A Third Term?", a debate between Roy Victor Peel and Raymond Moley, 10 pp., Feb 22, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 21)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:124
    - "America's Policy in a Warring World", a debate between Norman Thomas and Rep. Emanuel Celler of New York, 14 pp., Apr 11, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 22)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:125
    - "Marx and Engels - The Heritage and the Challenge", the first lecture in a series entitled, "Prophets Of Our Time", by Sidney Hook, 24 pp., Feb 3, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 23)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:126
    - "Bakunin", a lecture in a series entitled, "Prophets of Our Time", by Dr. Rudolph Rocker, 39pp. (2 copies)., Feb 10, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 24)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:127
    - "Gandhi: Uncertain Star of the East", the sixth lecture in a series entitled, "Prophets of our Time", by Bertrand Russell, 29 pp., Mar 9, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 25)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:128
    - "Trotsky and Stalin", a lecture in a series entitled, "Prophets of Our Time", by Bertram D. Wolfe, 44 pp., Mar 23, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 26)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:129
    - "Lecture on Theory of the Leisure Class(Veblen)", a lecture in a series entitled, "Books That Have Made History", by Jacob Axelrad, 25 pp., Dec 6, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 27)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:130
    - "Lecture on Aeropagitica(Milton), A Poet's Plea for Freedom of the Press", a lecture in a series entitled, "Books That Have Made History", by William H. Chamberlin, 26 pp., Oct 18, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 28)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:131
    - "Lecture on Thus Spake Zarathustra(Nietzsche)", a lecture in a series entitled, "Books That Have Made History", by Francis Hackett, 23 pp., Nov 29, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 29)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:132
    - "Lecture on Democracy and Education(Dewey)", a lecture in a series entitled, "Books That Have Made History", by Sidney Hook, 28 pp., Dec 13, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:133
    - "Lecture on Psychoanalysis (Freud), New Frontiers of Science", a lecture in a series entitled, "Books That Have Made History", by Dr. Bela Mittleman, 22 pp., Nov 15, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:134
    - "Lecture on Origin of Species (Darwin), Fundamental Revolution in Thought", a lecture in a series entitled, "Books That Have Made History", by John H. Randall, Jr., 26 pp., Nov 1, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:135
    - "Lecture on The Social Contract (Rousseau), Battle Cry of Political Democracy", a lecture in a series entitled, "Books That Have Made History", by J. Salwyn Schapiro, 27 pp., Oct 25, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:136
    - "Lecture on City of God (St. Augustine), A Vindi­cation of Christianity", a lecture in a series entitled, "Books That Have Made History", by Dr. George N. Shuster, 25 pp., Oct 11, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:137
    - "World Peace--America's Role", a Round-Table Dis­cussion with William Henry Chamberlin, Kenneth G. Crawford, and Sidney Hook, 41 pp., Oct 3, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:138
    - "Palestine--And The Future of the Jews", a Round­Table Discussion with Rabbi Elmer Berger, Eliahu Epstein, Moshe Furmansky, G. Kheirallah, I. N. Steinberg, and Bertram D. Wolfe, 51 pp., Oct 10, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:139
    - "Russia's Hegemony--In Eastern Europe and the Balkans", a Round-Table Discussion with David J. Dallin, Leon Dennen, Henry Pratt Fairchild, and Michael Karpovich, 55 pp., Oct 24, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:140
    - "Asia--Football of Power Politics", a Round-Table Discussion with Dr. Takaranath Das, Harry Paxton Howard, and David J. Dallin, 32 pp., Oct 31, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:141
    - "Sixty Million Jobs--A Factor in World Peace", a Round-Table Discussion with A. Philip Randolph, Dr. William Withers, Prof. Irving Fisher, and William Irvine, 59 pp., Nov 14, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:142
    - "Has Propaganda Any Value in Education?", a debate between Scott Nearing and Alexis Ferm, 13 pp., undated (Box 37, Folder 11)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:143
  - Subseries IIID: Manuscripts, 1931-1950
    Manuscripts, consists of 25 subject files. The items in this part are arranged in alphabetical order according to the author's last name or the title of the manuscript. Many of the manuscripts were written for various Rand School courses and lectures. The most prominent items in this part are James T. Farrell's essay on socialism and workers' education (XIII:C:150), Feliks Gross's essay on social empiricism (XIII:C:154), W. R. Malinowski's article on socialist proposals for world peace (XIII:C:158), Max Nomad's essay on American labor movements (XIII:C:162), and Mark Starr's essay on George Bernard Shaw and the Fabians (XIII:C:165). There are also three term papers in this part which were written by Rand School students (XIII:C:166).
    - Braunthal, Alfred, "America Is Not Europe", 6pp., undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:144
    - Coldwell, Joseph M., "Clarence Darrow and Eugene V. Debs", 8pp., undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:145
    - Coldwell, M. J., "Labour, Socialism, and Liberalism: An Analysis and a Forecast for Europe and America", 11 pp., Dec 6, 1944 (Box 37, Folder 14)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:146
    - Cole, Mrs. G. D. H., "Planning for Socialism in Britain", 14 pp., Oct 13, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 15)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:147
    - Dan, Th., "Die Geschicke Des Bolschewismus", 11 pp., undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:148
    - "New Road to a New World", 8pp., Feb 26, 1943 (Box 37, Folder 17)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:149
    - Farrell, James T., "Socialism and Workers Education", l6pp., ca.Mar 31, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 18)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:150
    - "Fascist and Semi-Fascist Groups in New England", l8pp., Late 1930s (Box 37, Folder 19)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:151
    - Fried, Hans E., "The Role of Democracy in Labor Relations: Experiences in Austria, 1918-1939", pp. 1-261. (International Institute of Social Research, NYC) (Box 37, Folder 20)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:152
    - Fried, Hans E., "The Role of Democracy in Labor Relations: Experiences in Austria, 1918-1939", pp. 1-261. (International Institute of Social Research, NYC) (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Fried, Hans E., "The Role of Democracy in Labor Relations: Experiences in Austria, 1918-1939", pp. 262-410. (International Institute of Social Research, NYC) (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Gross, Feliks, "An Empirical Approach to Social Change (Problems of Democratic Socialism and Communism) ", 24pp., undated (Box 37, Folder 23)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:153
    - "Social Empiricism", 48pp., ca.1950 (Box 37, Folder 24)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:154
    - Hart, Joseph, "Our Public Education and its Social Background", 9pp., undated (Box 37, Folder 25)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:155
    - Hu Shih, "Sun Yat-sen", l4pp., Mar 2, 1944 (Box 37, Folder 26)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:156
    - Kobbe, Herman, "Solving the Housing Problem With Special Application to New York State", 21pp., 1931 (Box 37, Folder 27)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:157
    - Malinowski, W. R., "Socialist Proposals for World Peace", 3pp., Mar 29, 1944 (Box 37, Folder 28)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:158
    - Mayer, Henry, "The Road to Reaction", l3pp., Feb 28, 1946 (Box 37, Folder 29)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:159
    - Morrison, Herbert, [A speech], l0pp., May 1, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 30)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:160
    - Morrison, Herbert, [A speech], 18 pp, ca.1936 (Box 37, Folder 31)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:161
    - Nomad, Max, "The Knights of Labor, the I.W.W., and the Anarchists", l8pp., undated (Box 37, Folder 32)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:162
    - Press, I. Puhge, "The History and Activities of the Rand School of Social Science", 24pp., May 16, 1934 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:163
    - [Manuscript on the history of the Rochdale Pioneer Cooperative Society], 41pp., undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:164
    - Starr, Mark, "Shaw and the Fabians", l3pp., Feb 24, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 45: Frame XIII:C:165
    - Student Papers: ' Nucatola, John P., "Democracy-Freedom, Contributions of France, England, and the Americas Towards Freedom in the 17th and 18th Century", 21pp., nd.; ' Rosen, Emanuel, "The Evolution of the Concerto", 10 pp., January 1941; ' "Wendell Phillips--Abolitionist", l2pp., nd., undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:C:166
    - Willis, H. Parker, "The Currency and Financial Policies of the National Administration" 13 pp., Oct 5, 1933 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:C:167
    - ["Young Circle League"], l7pp., undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:C:168
- Series IV: Financial Records, 1912-1955
  The financial records of the Rand School consist of six subject files. Among the various types of materials found in this series are correspondence, audits and treasurer's reports, bequests and wills, concert benefit papers, lists of contributors to the sustaining fund, and the one Third of a Century Fund papers. The items within these files are arranged in chronological order, with undated items placed at the end of the file. The bulk of the materials in this series pertains to the audits and treasurer's reports (XIII:D:2) and concert benefits (XIII:D:4). The audits and treasurer's reports offer general financial information about receipts and expenditures for the various departments within the Rand School. The concert benefits file contains correspondence and financial statements relating to the Metropolitan Opera and Broadway show performances which were held annually on behalf of the Rand School.
  - Correspondence, Jan 27, 1943-Dec 28, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:D:1
  - Correspondence, Jan 4, 1946-Sep 9, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1912-1913 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:D:2
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1920-1921 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1922-1923 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1924 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1925 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1926 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1927 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1928 (Box 38, Folder 16)